Quinn Pfeifer

Software Engineer

Hard Skills

Programming Languages: Java, C++, C#, Python, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, NodeJS, React, and MongoDB

Math: Calculus 1, 2, and 3, along with Linear Algebra

Other Software Skills: Data structures, databases, version control, computer vision, automation with trajectory planning, interfacing with APIs; libraries; and motors/sensors, Android app development, PID control

Soft Skills

- Working collaboratively in software development with strict deadlines
- Teaching, lesson planning, written and oral communication
- Leadership, conflict resolution
- Critical thinking, problem-solving, and attention to detail

Volunteer Work

I have volunteered for hundreds of hours at FIRST Robotics competitions, spreading my passion for STEM to younger students. I also worked with my FRC Robotics team to present at outreach events at museums and fairs to share our enthusiasm for robotics and promote STEM with the broader community.

Student at the **University of Washington's Paul G. Allen School of Computer Science**. Multiple years of experience in **Robotics**, **Web Development**, and **Leadership** in **Software Engineering**

Education

Henry M. Jackson High School

Sept 2019 – June 2023

High School Diploma, Valedictorian (GPA: 4.0) Member of FIRST Robotics Team 2910

Everett Community College (Running Start)

Sept 2021 – June 2023

Associate in Art and Science, President's Distinction (GPA: 4.0)

University of Washington, Seattle

Sept 2023 - Present

Paul G. Allen School of Computer Science

Awards and Honors

- FRC Autonomous Award Sponsored by Ford (twice in 2022, once in 2023)
- 2023 Indiana Robotics Invitational Scholar, IRI Host Teams Scholarship
- AP Scholar, AP Scholar with Honor

Experience

Computer Science Teacher - Coding With Kids

Aug 2021 – April 2023

At Coding With Kids premier coding academy, I tutored young children in the basics of computer programming in languages like Scratch and Python. I was responsible for planning lessons, writing lesson reports, report cards, and working with parents to ensure a top-tier education for their children.

Lead Software Developer – FRC Team 2910

Sept 2021 – July 2023

In high school, I was a member of a world-class robotics team. We finished 3rd place in the world in 2022 and won over 10 major competitions over the 2022 and 2023 seasons. On this team, I wrote award-winning autonomous code and had the opportunity to work closely with mentors who are industry experts (Microsoft, Boeing, and more). I picked up skills like computer vision, autonomous motion and trajectory planning, PID control, and even Android app development.